micasense.com 2019-10-12

# Privacy Policy — MicaSense

This Privacy Policy is intended to inform you of the MicaSense, Inc., a California Corporation ("MicaSense") policies and practices regarding the collection, use and disclosure of any Personal Information you submit to us through www.micasense.com (the "Website").

"Personal Information" is information about you that is personally identifiable to you, like your name, address, email address, or phone number, as well as other non-public information that is associated with the foregoing.

By submitting Personal Information through our Website, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the processing of your Personal Information according to this Privacy Policy. Your Personal Information may be processed by MicaSense in the country where it was collected as well as transferred to and processed in other countries (including the United States) where laws regarding processing of Personal Information may be less stringent than the laws in your country.

 **The Data We Collect and How We Use it**

Information You Choose to Give

  * When you sign up for an account with MicaSense or sign up for content or offers, we may ask you to provide Personal Information such as your email address and password.

  * When purchasing our products, you may be required to provide additional Personal Information including your name, phone number, postal address and/or payment information such as your bank account, credit or debit card number. We do not retain your payment information within our systems, nor do we ever have access to it explicitly.

  * When you sign up for content or offers from us, we may also ask that you provide information such as your name, email address and details about your organization

  * When you register on the Website, we will collect your full name, email address, phone number, and your organization (if associated with an organization).

When you contact us to submit comments, questions or feedback using the forms on the Website or in the Website, we will collect your name, email address and your comment, question or feedback.

  * When you contact us by sending us an email, we will collect your email address and any information contained in the email you send us and any information attached to the email.

  * If you provide feedback on any of our products and services to us, we may use such feedback for any purpose, provided we will not associate such feedback with your Personal Information. MicaSense will collect any information contained in such communication and will treat the Personal Information in such communication in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

As otherwise detailed in this Privacy Policy, we will solely process this information to provide you with the service you’ve signed up for.

You may unsubscribe from receiving content or offers from us and/or deactivate your MicaSense Atlas account at any time.

Should you decide to deactivate your account with us or request that we permanently remove you from our mailing list, we may retain your Personal Information in order to meet any regulatory and reporting requirements and to address any customer service issues. Any other Personal Information would be deleted permanently within 30 days.

 **Information Collected Automatically**

When visiting our Website, interacting with our content, or using your MicaSense account, we collect...  

 **Usage Data:** When you visit our Website, we capture the name of your internet service provider, the Website from which you visited us from, the pages of the Website you visit, the date and duration of your visit, and information from the device (device type, operating system, screen resolution, language, country you are located in, and web browser type) used during your visit (“Usage Data”). We only capture and store a truncated version of your IP address. Your full IP address never reaches our servers and we never have access to it.

We use this data to facilitate and improve upon your access to our services and Website (e.g. to adjust the services to the device you are using), and to recognize and stop any misuse. We also process Usage Data in an anonymized form for statistical purposes and to improve the Website. In addition, we use behavioral data that is automatically collected to improve and personalize our services.

Cookies: We use cookies to process information including standard internet log information and details of visitor’s behavioral patterns upon visiting the Website. MicaSense stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Cookies are stored on your individual device and you have full control over their use.

We use cookies to provide you with a better experience, and to facilitate the use of certain functions. MicaSense does not process this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user.

You may deactivate or restrict the transmission of cookies by changing the settings of your web browser. Cookies that are already stored may be deleted at any time. Should you visit our Website with cookies deactivated, you may possibly not be able to use all of the functions on the Website to the full extent. Please refer to items 3 & 4 below for further details.

Contact via e-mails: On the Website, you can contact us via the contact form. In that form, we ask for your contact information (e.g. name, email address etc.). If you choose to receive e-mails from us, we may use certain analytics tools to capture data such as when you open our email or if you click on any links or banners in our e-mail.

We may also occasionally send you notification emails about updates to our products, legal documents, or offer customer support or marketing emails. Except for cases where we are required to do so by law (e.g. notifying you of a data breach), you shall have the opportunity to unsubscribe from receiving these messages free of charge.

We use this data solely to answer questions we receive or to help us improve on the effectiveness of our communications and marketing campaigns.

 **We share some Personal Information with a few third parties**

Except as otherwise stated in this Privacy Policy, we do not trade, rent, or share your Personal Information with third parties. However, we may share your Personal Information with third parties to provide you with the products and services that we offer you through the Website.

We use a few trusted external service providers for data analysis, processing and/or storage offerings. These service providers are carefully selected and meet high data protection and security standards.

We only share information with them..

(i) if you have provided prior consent

(ii) if its required to achieve the purpose for which we have contracted these services

(iii) if we are obliged to do so by law or an instruction by a public authority or court

(iv) upon the sale of our business  

These third parties are required not to use your Personal Information other than to provide the products and services requested by MicaSense and are bound by confidentiality agreements with regard to their use of such information. You expressly consent to the sharing of your Personal Information with our contractors and third party service providers for the sole purpose of providing products and services to you.

We may share some or all of your Personal Information with companies under common control such as any subsidiaries or joint ventures (collectively, "Affiliates"), in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.

If our company or our assets are acquired by another company, that company will possess the Personal Information collected by us and it will assume the rights and obligations regarding your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy.

Regardless of any choices you make regarding your Personal Information (as described below), we may disclose your Personal Information if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on MicaSense; or (b) to protect and defend the rights or property of MicaSense or users of our Services.

 **Your California Privacy Rights**

If you are a California resident, you may request and obtain from us, once a year, free of charge, certain information about the Personal Information (if any) we disclosed to third parties for their marketing purposes in the preceding calendar year. This information would include a list of the categories of Personal Information that we shared and the names and mailing addresses of all third parties with which we shared Personal Information in the preceding calendar year. If you would like to make such a request, please submit your request to Customer Support.

 **Your Choices Regarding Your Personal Information**

In line with the law, you have the right to be informed of your Personal Information processed by MicaSense, a right to rectification and/or correction, and a right of erasure and/or restriction of processing. You have also the right to receive from MicaSense a structured, common and machine-readable format of the Personal Information you provided to us.

When you receive promotional communications from us, you may indicate a preference to stop receiving further communications from us and you will have the opportunity to "opt-out" by following the unsubscribe instructions provided in the communication you receive or by contacting us directly (please see contact information below).

You may at any time change and/or withdraw your consent regarding any use or processing of your Personal Information, without affecting the lawfulness of the processing that was carried out prior to withdrawing it.

To this end, you may simply log onto your account, access your profile and make the desired changes or, should this option not be available, please contact our support team at [support@micasense.com](mailto:support@micasense.com)

Whenever you withdraw your consent, you acknowledge and agree that this may have a negative influence on the quality of the Website and/or the services we provide. You further acknowledge and agree that MicaSense shall not be held liable with respect to any loss and/or damage to your Personal Information if you choose to withdraw consent.

 **Regarding Children**

We do not intentionally gather Personal Information about visitors who are under the age of 13. By accessing the Website, you represent that you are over the age of 13.

 **Other Sites**

Our provision of a link to any other site or location is for your convenience and does not signify our endorsement of such other site or location or its contents. We have no control over, do not review, and cannot be responsible for these outside sites or their content. Please be aware that the terms of our Privacy Policy do not apply to these outside sites.

 **Security and Retention of Personal Information**

MicaSense is committed to protecting the security of your Personal Information. Even though MicaSense makes efforts to ensure that your Personal Information is not intercepted, accessed, used, or disclosed by unauthorized persons, you should know that MicaSense cannot fully eliminate security risks associated with Personal Information.

We will store your Usage Data until such time when you withdraw your consent for us to do so. All other data and Personal Information as specified above will be retained for as long as is necessary for the purpose(s) for which we originally collected it. We may also retain information and/or data as required by law.

 **Contact Us**

Should you have any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, or would like to issue a complaint, please contact us through Customer Support or:

MicaSense, Inc.

1300 N Northlake Way, Suite 100

Seattle WA 98103

 **Privacy Policy Updates**

This Privacy Statement is a living document. As part of the MicaSense Terms and Conditions, this Privacy Policy is subject to occasional amendment, in accordance with the terms of the Terms and Conditions.

This Policy was last updated on May 25, 2018
